Guide to the Stanford Alpine Club Scrapbook SC0668
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Alpine Club scrapbook
1947-1965
bulk
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Alpine Club
SC0668
2.75 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
The scrapbook contains primarily newsclippings, photographs, and miscellaneous records of Stanford Alpine Club activities in the early 1950s.
Scope and Contents note
The scrapbook contains primarily newsclippings, photographs, and miscellaneous records of Stanford Alpine Club activities in the early 1950s. Individuals pictured include David Harrah, John Logan, Larry Taylor, John Mowat, and Bea Vogel. Also includes a letter from Bertrand Russell, President of the Mountaineering Association of Britain, 1952.
Ownership and Custodial History
The scrapbook was given to Stanford University in 1982 by Dick Simpson.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Student activities.; Mountaineering; Harrah, David.; Logan, John K.; Mowat, John Gordon.; Stanford Alpine Club; Taylor, Larry.; Vogel, Beatrice R.
- Clippings, assorted (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Dave Harrah, Gates Creek - photographs (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Dave Harrah, Pinnacles - photographs, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Clippings, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Prussik at Miraloma - photograph, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Clipping, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Clippings and photographs ("Eagle's Nest route, Hunter Hill, Vallejo, CA) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- John Logan, Indian Rock (Tyrolean traverse) - photograph, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Larry Taylor, Miraloma Rock - photographs, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Rescue techniques, Gragmont, Sierra Club RCS outing - photographs, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Yerupaja - photographs, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Practice climb (includes Bill Shirley, John Mowat, Nick Clinch) - photograph, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bea Vogel, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Coast Range expedition - photographs, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Rébuffat film on climbing - clipping, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous - old caption, two postcards from Al Baxter, clipping (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Membership list - approved leaders, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Clippings, postcard, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Clippings re Yerupaja climb by Dave Harrah, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous clippings and one photo of Cathedral Spire (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Club photo for Quad photo, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Two postcards from the Tetons and two unidentified photographs (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Clippings, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Photos of climbing practice 1952, letter from Bertrand Russell (president of the Mountaineering Association of Britain) re training opportunities [original in box 2, folder 4], and two miscellaneous items (Box 1, Folder 24)
- "Die Luft der Freiheit Wehr" - one poem (by Jim Moore) and assorted drawings (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Clippings, 1954-55, and one photograph, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Clippings re climbing deaths [original of 1 in box 2, folder 4] (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous: photographs, clippings, and humorous list of gift suggestions for individual SAC members (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Drawings and miscellany [original for 1 set of drawings in box 2, folder 4] (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Loose items: two postcards from Carolyn Teren, 1952, clippings (mostly cartoons), and three unidentified photographs (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Beach party - slides, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Beach field trip, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Photographs - unidentified person climbing (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Canadian Rockies: Dick Irvin, John Mowat, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Shasta Thanksgiving Climb, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Original Stanford Daily re death of Hopf, 1953 Nov 30 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Original clippings (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Photocopied clippings (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Original documents removed from box 1 [drawings, B. Russell letter, clipping] (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Daumier print labeled "Cox & Kroger - Looking Though the Scrapbook" (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Scrapbook pages 29-30 (assorted clippings) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Life magazine article on Jon Lindbergh, 1952 Oct 27 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Original scrapbook binding (Box 3)
- Additional materials, Accession ARCH-2017-182
  - Photograph (Box 1)